Lady Amira?!
To think that humans alone could protect the God Key...
Jeanne D'Arc...
She may indeed be capable of becoming a holy knight.
The battle surrounding Bahamut will surely end when she does—
No. We will be the ones to end it.
We've yet to figure out who the demon
mastermind is or what they're trying to achieve.
However, I expect that will come to light very soon...
As long as we have the God Key.
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
Let me see the sun
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
（アーミラ）
きゃあああ！
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
（カイザル）
アーミラ嬢？
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
（ウリエル）
まさか 人間の力だけで
鍵を護(まも)り抜くとは…
It's too late if you want to do something
（ラファエル）
ジャンヌ･ダルクか…
What the hell is wrong with me?
あの人間ならば
聖なる騎士となりうるやもしれん
I can't remember what I wanted to be
（ミカエル）
そのときは
バハムートを巡る争いにも
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
幕が下りよう…
（ガブリエル）
いえ
幕は我ら神の手で下ろすのです
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
首謀者たる悪魔の正体と目的は
まだ暴けていません
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
ですが それも
まもなく明らかになるでしょう
I'm the only one
“神の鍵”があるかぎり
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
（シャリオス）
聖なる乙女 ジャンヌよ
O Jeanne, maiden of holiness.
You have fought magnificently yet again.
此度(こたび)の働きも実に見事であった
As reward, I will grant you territory of your own.
褒美として 領地を与えよう
What would you like? Baruzo? Ruelle?
どこがいい？
バルゾか？　ルエールか？
（ジャンヌ）
恐れながら ご辞退いたします
Thank you, but I'm afraid I must decline.
今 何と？
You... what?
There is one thing I would humbly like to request, however.
その代わり
かなえていただきたきことが１つ
（カイザル）
気が付いたかい？
Are you awake?
How did I...
（アーミラ）
私…
You suddenly fainted for reasons unknown.
（カイザル）
理由は分からないが
突然 倒れたのだ
It's obviously 'cause she drank too much.
（ファバロ）
理由なら分かるさ
酒の飲み過ぎだ
（リタ）
違うと思うけど
I don't think so.
夢 見てた…
I had a dream...
繭(まゆ)から目覚めたときの
of when I woke from my cocoon.
Cocoon?
繭？
I was asleep in a cocoon for a long time.
私… ずっと繭の中で眠ってた
（マルチネ）
目覚めなさい アーミラ
Wake, Amira.
You are special.
（マルチネ）
あなたは特別な存在です
Special?
とく… べつ？
Fulfill your mission, Amira.
（マルチネ）
使命を果たすのです アーミラ
Do so, and your wish will surely come true...
そうすれば
あなたの願いは かなうでしょう
In the promised land of Helheim.
約束の地“ヘルヘイム”で
ヘル… ヘイム
Helheim...
What you seek is surely there.
（マルチネ）
あなたの求めるものが
きっと そこに
（アーミラ）
おかあ… さん
Mother...
That pendant holds your mother's memories?
（ファバロ）
そのペンダントに
母ちゃんの記憶が？
That's why you're going to Helheim?
（カイザル）
それで ヘルヘイムに…
お父さん！
Father!
Whoa! Hold on!
おい 待てって！
Where do you think you're going?!
どこに行くつもりだ？
お父さんが私のこと呼んでた
My father was calling for me!
Calm down!
落ち着け！
I know you wanna see your dad,
but if you go wandering off again...
父ちゃんに会いてえのは分かる
けど
またウロウロしてたら めんど…
（ゴラン）
父親とは 誰の話だ？
Who is this father you speak of?
Oh, it's nothing important.
（ファバロ）
いや…
こっちの話だ
Do you need something?
俺たちに何か？
シャリオス王が
貴様らを お呼びだ
King Charioce wishes to see you.
Huh?
What is the meaning of this?
一体 何が始まるのだ？
（リタ）
もしかして
今度こそ 死刑宣告だったりして
Who knows? Maybe he's finally going to sentence us to death.
ゾンビが縁起でもねえこと
言ってんじゃねえよ
Don't talk like that, zombie. You'll jinx us.
何だよ？
What is it?
あそこに お父さんが！
That's my father over there!
That's Jeanne D'Arc's lieutenant.
（リタ）
あれって
ジャンヌ･ダルクの副官でしょ？
Father!
（アーミラ）
お父さん…
（ファバロ）
騒ぐな！　慌てるな
Chill out for a second!
Are you sayin' that big shot is your dad?
てか そんな偉いヤツが
お前の父ちゃん？
If so, that would mean he isn't human.
それが事実なら あの人
人間じゃないってことになるわ
Then he's a demon?
もしかして… 悪魔？
No.
（カイザル）
いや
そんなはずはない
He can't be.
Yeah! He can't be!
ああ そんなはずはない
（ファバロ）おおっ…
（リタ）どっちよ
Make up your mind.
前に 一度 会ったことがあるのだ
ワイトアープの町で
I met him once before in the city of Wytearp.
The desire for something can make a person strong.
（ラヴァレイ）
何かを望む心は人を強くする
Never forget that.
それを忘れるな
He saved me when my heart had turned dissolute.
（カイザル）
すさんだ私の心を救ってくれた
He's a proud, honorable knight.
彼は立派な誇り高き騎士だ
Favaro Leone. Kaisar Lidfard.
（シャリオス）
ファバロ･レオーネ
カイザル･リドファルド
I render unto you the following.
その両名に言い渡す
For your recent heroic deeds,
此度の働きに対し
騎士の称号を与える
I grant you both knighthood.
Huh?!
騎士の… 称号？
Knighthood?!
Uh, being a knight is way more of a hassle than I—
（ファバロ）
いや
俺は騎士とか そうゆう面倒な…
We gratefully accept!
（カイザル）
ありがたく お受けいたします！
（ファバロ）
おい！
Hey!
ハア…
（側近）
では これより 叙任式を執り行う
The appointment ceremony will now take place.
In the name of the king,
（シャリオス）
そちたち２人を我が名において
オルレアン騎士団の一員に任ずる
you two are hereby appointed to the Orléans Knights.
You do me too much honor!
（カイザル）
身に余る光栄！
It's an honor.
光栄です…
I've finally fulfilled my oath!
やっと… 誓いを果たせた
賞金稼ぎに戻ることもないだろう
I doubt I'll ever go back to bounty hunting!
Too bad.
残念
That thing ain't coming off
even if you try and demolish it.
そいつは壊せても
外すことはできねえよ
What?!
That drunkard is the only one who can take it off.
そいつを外せんのは
あの酔っ払いだけだ
（バッカス）
ぶえっ…
（バッカス）バカヤロー！
（ハンサ）くわっ！
These are the valiant warriors
who battled the demon with you.
（シャリオス）
そちと共に悪魔と戦いし
勇敢なる者たちか…
I've no doubt they will make our knights even stronger.
これで我が騎士団も
更に強くなるであろうな
You are too kind.
（ジャンヌ）
恐れ入ります
L-Lord Michael!
ミ… ミカエル様！
You have done truly well, O valiant ones.
勇猛なる者たちよ
此度の働き 誠に見事だった
あ… ありがたき お言葉
Y-You honor us with your words!
With the key's seal lifted, we can expect greater activity from demonkind.
鍵の封印が解けたことで
魔の者たちの動きも
より活発になっていくだろう
The Précieuse, a sword of malevolence and blessedness, capable of slaying even gods.
（ミカエル）
プレシューズ
神ですら斬ることができる邪聖の剣
Jeanne, I bestow it upon you.
ジャンヌ あなたに授けます
Use its power righteously.
その力 正しく使いなさい
I shall.
心して…
Uh, what about me?
あの 私めには…
既に 祈りの言葉は聞き届けた
I have heard your prayers.
I pledge that your beliefs and endeavors will have the gods' blessings.
そなたたちの信仰と活躍に
神の加護を約束しよう
ハア…
How pathetic, Azazel.
（ベルゼビュート）
無様だな アザゼル
Beelzebub!
（アザゼル）
ベルゼ… ビュート！
Y-You...
You deceived me!
たば… かったなあ！
（ベルゼビュート）
貴様の役目は終わった
You're finished.
（アザゼル）
ルシフェル様を裏切り
何を たくらんでいる…
What are you scheming,
betraying Lord Lucifer like this?!
You'll know soon enough, when the time comes.
（ベルゼビュート）
じきに分かる　そのときが来れば
When the time comes?
その… とき？
審判の日だ
Judgment Day.
（シャリオス）
ジャンヌめ…
Curse you, Jeanne.
As their proxy, only the king of Anatae is allowed the privilege of having an audience with the gods.
神々との拝謁は
アナティ王だけに許された
特別な権限
What's more, she not only rejected my offer to her,
代行者たる余の申し出を
断るばかりか
but Lord Michael granted her a sword, as well.
ミカエル様から剣を賜るとは…
Please tell me, Mother!
教えてください 母上
Who is the most beloved and
revered in the Royal Capital?!
この王都で最も愛され
崇められる者は誰なのです？
You must be careful, Charioce.
（イザベリア）
気をつけるのです シャリオス
Mother!
母上！
A traitor aims to take your life.
（イザベリア）
裏切り者が
あなたの命を狙っています
My life?
（シャリオス）
余の命を？
But, who?!
一体 誰が…
You know the answer.
知っているでしょ
ほら！
Look!
Jeanne D'Arc!
（シャリオス）
ジャンヌ… ダルク
ひゃあああ！
What you have seen will happen very soon.
今のは近い未来の出来事
Jeanne will kill you and become ruler of this land.
ジャンヌは あなたを殺して
この国の王になる
Her? The ruler of this land?
Jeanne! Jeanne! Jeanne!
ヤツが… この国の王に？
（民衆）
ジャンヌ！　ジャンヌ！
Saint Jeanne is the light of Anatae!
（男Ａ）
ジャンヌ様こそ アナティの光！
She is our beacon of peace of prosperity!
（男Ｂ）
平和と繁栄をもたらすお方！
I won't allow it. I won't allow it!
（シャリオス）
許さぬ… 許さぬぞ
I am the king.
王は… この余だ
（ファバロ）
おい
Hey.
Y-You're choking me...
Oh.
（ファバロ）
ゲホッ…
Ow...
いってえ～
Seriously, I told you not to wander around.
言っただろ ウロウロするなって
I'm sorry. It's just...
（アーミラ）
ごめんなさい　でも…
You insist on seeing your father?
（リタ）
父親に
どうしても会いたいってわけね
Yeah.
Man...
たく…
Let's go.
行くぞ
The barracks aren't this way.
（リタ）
宿舎は こっちじゃないわよ
No, it's okay.
（ファバロ）
いや いいんだ
Your old man is up there.
あそこに お前の親父(おやじ)さんがいる
Really?
You wanna see him, right?
（ファバロ）
どうしても会いてえんだろ？
Then go on already.
なら とっとと行けって
Okay!
Thanks, Fava!
ありがとう ファバ
I can't believe it.
あいつ…
That's the first time she's ever said my name.
初めて名前を呼びやがった
Left off the "ro," though.
“ロ”が抜けてたけどな
Whoa! Hold on, zombie girl!
て… おい こら！　ゾンビ娘！
（リタ）
だって 気になるでしょ
I can't help it. I don't want to miss this.
All right...
（ファバロ）
まあな…
U-Um...
（アーミラ）
あ… あの…
I missed you, Amira.
会いたかったぞ アーミラ
Father?
おとう… さん
You've grown so much in just five years.
たった５年で こんなに大きく…
F-Five years?!
（ファバロ）
ご… ５年！
Eh, sorry.
いや～ つい…
I'm glad you brought Amira all the way here.
君たちも よくぞ アーミラを
ここまで連れてきてくれた
I, Lavalley, thank you sincerely for saving her life.
恩人に代わって このラヴァレイ
心から礼を言う
Saving her life?
恩人？
Listen closely, Amira.
アーミラ よく聞きなさい
I have something important to tell you about you and your mother.
お前と
お前の母にまつわる大事な話だ
The war gods have been wiped out?!
（ガブリエル）
軍神たちが全滅？
This doesn't seem to be Azazel's doing.
（ミカエル）
アザゼルの仕業とは思えません
I believe it was...
恐らく…
...the mastermind behind the Key's theft.
（ガブリエル）
鍵を奪わせた黒幕でしょう
What shall we do, Gabriel?
（ミカエル）
いかがいたします？　ガブリエル
（ガブリエル）
王都の護衛を徹底してください
Ensure that the Royal Capital is secure.
We must prevent the key girl from being taken at all costs.
鍵の娘が奪われることだけは
何としても避けねばなりません
If it wasn't Lucifer...
（ガブリエル）
ルシフェルとは別の勢力…
then who could it be?
一体 誰が？
It's been a long time, Beelzebub.
（ルシフェル）
久しぶりだね ベルゼビュート
Azazel has failed miserably.
（ベルゼビュート）
アザゼルが しくじった
We can afford no more blundering, Lucifer.
これ以上の失態は まかりならぬぞ
ルシフェル
A pity.
（ルシフェル）
それは残念
じゃあ 別の誰かを…
I'll just send someone else, then.
（ベルゼビュート）
それには及ばぬ
No need. I will take over from here.
後は我が引き継ごう
You will?
（ルシフェル）
わざわざ 君が？
Do you object?
不服かな？
No.
いや
We will retrieve the key girl and revive Lord Satan without fail.
（ベルゼビュート）
必ずや鍵の娘を取り戻し
サタン様の復活を我らの手で
Amira is special.
（ラヴァレイ）
アーミラは特別な存在…
She was born of an angel and a demon. She's half of both.
天使と悪魔の間に生まれた
半身半魔なのだ
What?!
You mean a god and a demon actually had a kid?!
つまり
神と悪魔が子供つくったってのか
Your parents are awesome! They kick ass!
お前の親 スゲえな やるじゃねえか
（リタ）
じゃあ あなたは？
What does that make you?
私はアーミラの父親ではない
I am not Amira's father.
ただの人間だ
I'm an ordinary human.
It happened many years ago.
（ラヴァレイ）
昔の話だ
I was assigned to be a
bodyguard for a certain angel...
私は
とある天使の護衛を任されていた
Your mother, Nicole.
それが お前の母 ニコールだ
She was strictly forbidden from ever returning to Heaven.
彼女は天界へ戻ることを
固く禁じられていた
それでも 赤子のお前と
一緒にいるニコールは
Even so, Nicole looked so happy to be with you.
とても幸せそうに見えた
Although we had grown weary from the relentless demon attacks,
度重なる悪魔の襲来で疲弊していた
私たちにとっても
you two—a mother and her
infant daughter—gave us hope.
お前たち母子は
生きる希望だったのだ
だが…
However...
さらわれた我が子を取り戻すため
Nicole left for the land of demons to retrieve her kidnapped daughter.
ニコールは魔の地へと旅立った
She gave me this pendant.
このペンダントは
彼女から渡されたもの
Having survived but relieved of duty,
一命を取り留め 任を解かれた私は
ニコールの行方を捜したが
I searched for Nicole, to no avail.
出会えることはなかった
However, on that particular day...
しかし あの日…
The pendant told me...
ペンダントが教えてくれたのだ
that you were Nicole's daughter.
お前がニコールの娘なのだと
I see.
なるほど
So the demons kidnapped the baby and sped up her growth.
悪魔が さらった赤ん坊を
急成長させたってわけね
That explains why she's way
more childish than she looks.
だから 見た目と違って
子供みてえだったのか
I was told over and over that I could see my mother if I stole the key!
（アーミラ）
私…
“鍵を盗めば お母さんに会える”
ずっと そう教えられてきた
The demons' power is strong in Helheim.
（ラヴァレイ）
ヘルヘイムは魔の力が強い土地
Although she's an angel, she wouldn't be able to stay there long.
天使といえども
長くとどまることはできない
Then where is my mother?!
じゃあ…
お母さんは どこに？
（ラヴァレイ）
アーミラ ペンダントを
Amira, give me your pendant.
ペンダントに
こんな仕掛けがあったなんて…
I had no idea it could do that.
Nicole is here.
ニコールがいる場所は ここだ
Prudisia, the Valley of Demons.
魔の谷“ブロドシア”
Heard of it?
知ってっか？
Nope.
さあ
This should lead you to Nicole.
これが ニコールの居場所を
示してくれるだろう
持っていきなさい
Take it.
The compass...
羅針盤… 今度は壊さない
I won't break it this time.
Your mother had an unusual power.
お前の母は不思議な力を持っていた
That's another reason the demons were after her.
悪魔に狙われていたのも
それが理由だ
It's possible that she, if anyone, can free you of the key.
彼女ならば
お前と鍵の因果を
解くことができるかもしれん
分かった… 私 行く
All right. I'll go!
What?! Are you serious?!
はあ？　マジか？
This means she can remove your tail.
これで尻尾 取れるんじゃない？
Yeah! You should definitely go!
そうだ！　行ったほうがいい
（ラヴァレイ）
できれば同行してやりたいのだが…
I wish I could accompany you, but...
I know. You're needed here.
分かってる
おじさんは ここに必要な人
（ラヴァレイ）
すまない
I'm sorry.
If you do meet her, please thank her for me.
もし会えたときには
私に代わって礼を
（アーミラ）
ダメ
No!
I'm bringing her back here. You can thank her yourself!
一緒に戻ってくるから
お母さんに言ってあげて
Yes.
（リタ）
意外とセンチなのね
You're surprisingly tenderhearted.
The thought of finally being rid of this tail...
（ファバロ）
これで やっと
尻尾が取れると思うとよ…
一緒に行く？　ブロドシア
Will you come with me to Prudisia?
No way in hell I'm going there!
（ファバロ）
行くわけねえだろ んなヤベえとこ
いやあ…
Nah, although I bet your
mom's really pretty and all!
アーミラの母ちゃん
さぞかし美人なんだろうな～
Would've been nice to meet her at least once!
一度 会ってみたかったなあ
ホント？
You're sure?
Sure I'm sure. Oh, what a shame.
（ファバロ）
ホントもホント
あ～ 残念だ
All right.
分かった
ハア…
で… カイザルには知らせないの？
So, aren't you going to tell Kaisar?
He's back to being a fancy-pants knight.
あいつは立派な騎士様に戻れたんだ
He's got no reason to hang around us anymore.
もう 俺たちとつるむ必要はねえさ
I guess we're your send-off party from Anatae, then.
アナティからは
俺たちだけで おさらばってな
I don't think sneaking out of
here will be that easy, though.
そんな簡単に抜け出せるとは
思えないけど
まさか…
It couldn't be!
（リタ）
まったく…
Honestly, now!
There's such a thing as being a zombie slave driver.
死人(しびと)使いが荒いにも程があるわ
The water channel under the city...
（ファバロ）
王都の地下水道か…
Gotta hand it to ol' Captain Lavalley.
さすが ラヴァレイ隊長
I can't believe that little white lie got me into all of this.
（ファバロ）
軽いうそが まさか ここまで
俺を翻弄(ほんろう)するとは…
But now it's all over!
だが それも終わった！
Okay! Take my tail off!
さあ 早く尻尾を
What? What hand gesture is that?
何だ？　その手の動きは
私のお母さんに会いたいんでしょ？
You want to meet my mother, right?
Huh?
Huh?!
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
What are the soldiers clamoring about?!
（シャリオス）
兵たちは何を騒ぎ立てておるのだ
Wh-Who goes there?!
だ… 誰じゃ？
Oh, it's just you.
なんじゃ そちか
ひやあああ！
Should I get dreadlocks, too?
（ジャンヌ）
私にもドレッドが似合うだろうか？
（ラヴァレイ）
いや 今のままで
You're fine as you are!
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis...
（ジャンヌ）
次回「神撃(しんげき)のバハムート GENESIS(ジェネシス)」
"Decision in the Wailing Woods."
（ラヴァレイ）
Decision(ディシジョン) in(イン) the(ザ) Wailing(ウェイリング) Woods(ウッズ)
Your answer cuts me deeply!
（ジャンヌ）
今の言葉 心に深くきたわ
Huh?
Illustration: Miyabi Kazashino
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week!